DOUGLAS HAWKINSON | Full Stack JavaScript Developer

Website: http://www.fivesolasdesign.com/

Greater Seattle, WA

(206) 910-3655 (cell)

http://www.linkedin.com/in/doug5solas

doug5solas@gmail.com

Reformed PMP Retooling Himself, A Leader By Example

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

After 25+ years on the management side of IT I retired. Retirement was not for me. I am coming back into the workplace, to produce, as a software developer. Attention to detail and my own drive to deliver provide the energy to achieve results. I ensure delivery through integrity and personal responsibility.

CORE COMPETENCIES

Software Development • Data Integration • Data Warehousing • ETL • Project Management • Business Analysis

CURRENT ONGOING TRAINING

HTML5 • CSS3 • responsive CSS • JavaScript/jQuery • Github • Webstorm • PHP • Python • Java

TECHNICAL SKILLS AND PLATFORMS

HTML5 • CSS3 • responsive CSS • JavaScript • Github • Webstorm • PHP • Python • Java SQL • MS SQL Server • Sybase • Oracle • MS Access MS Project • MS Office • MS Visio • MS SharePoint (2003, 2007, 2010) • Planview OSX/iOS • Windows OS • OS 390 TriZetto FACETS • Cerner • PeopleSoft Financials (Interface) • Oracle Financials (Interface)

EXPERIENCE

Retired - Seattle WA Student at TeamTreehouse - Online Student at Free Code Camp - Online 1/2014 - Date

9/2015 - Date

4/2016 - Date

Successfully completing online training in the following technologies. Began interacting with sites like MDN, CSS-Tricks, WC3, Github and others. Following two complementary tracks for the sake of comprehensiveness.

- Track Front End Web Development; Treehouse
- Track Full Stack JavaScript Tech Degree; Treehouse
- Track Full Stack Web Developer; Free Code Camp
- As Needed Python, PHP, Ruby, Rails;

VanderHouwen & Associates - Bellevue, WA

6/2013 - 12/2013

Sr. Project Manager

Contractual engagement to Seattle Children's Hospital. Utilized SharePoint 2007/2010 for project communications.

- Saved the company \$27,000 over original purchase agreement by skillful negotiations with vendor.
- Managed project automating account provisioning/de-provisioning. Cut costs by automating repetitive
- Effectively managed regional clinic migration from a paper system to automated Clinical Information System.
- Successfully managed automation of HR Performance Review process from RFP through Vendor selection.

Ergo Business Solutions – Seattle, WA (Sabbatical)

1/2013 – 6/2013

Managed the furniture side of Ergo Business Solutions, Inc. and provided surgical recovery home care for my wife.

Ergo Business Solutions – Seattle, WA

6/2005 - 12/2012

Senior Project Manager/Contractor (often with Mediant Health Resources)

Delivered strategic leadership, planning, budgeting, and risk mitigation strategies in matrixed management environments. Utilized multiple SDLC Methodologies, provided Business Analysis, produced RFPs.

- Conserved limited resources by managing multiple simultaneous projects with budgets exceeding \$10M.
- Increased client revenues by \$12M annually by effective project management of software enhancement.
- Often utilized SQL technologies in user-aceptance testing.

First Consulting Group - Long Beach, CA Manager, Implementations

9/1999 - 5/2005

Led critical technology projects providing design concepts to integrate legacy systems with vendor-supplied systems (Facets™), including assessments to determine appropriate middle-ware services and software solutions. Performed HR type functions such as Hiring/Review/Firing as part of management team.

- Secured engagements resulting in \$3M in revenues for employer firm.
- Developed long-term architecture requirements for IT Department of a large national HMO.
- Facilitated Data Warehouse design by providing expert source data consulting to client.
- Effectively reduced extraction errors on Data Warehouse project by effective database training.
- Became the firm's "go to" consulting resource on 3rd Party platform migrations.
- Successfully managed data migration (ETL) projects for clients with budgets up to \$15M.
- Established firm's best practices for data conversions/interfaces making the process reproducible.
- Created ETL templates utilizing SQL technologies as part of data conversions toolkit

Various Employers – CA and WA

Pre 1999

Consultant, Departmental Manager, Entrepreneur

Held various positions that increased my exposure to perspectives on solving business challenges such as:

- Successfully managed or participated as a team member on approximately 20 software implementation projects, including approximately 35 ETL sub-projects utilizing SQL. (ERISCO)
- Successfully managed a system make/buy decision through RFP, vendor selection, purchase and implementation. (Pacificare Behavioral Health)
- Cast vision for, then managed project to build Operational Data Store thereby improving ability to analyze operational costs. Doubled as Project and Departmental Manager of 25 FTEs and Contractors. (FHP)
- Successfully created an ongoing software venture that supported revenues of \$2M, creating jobs for 12 persons and managing development staff of 6 people. (SureCare Systems)
- Successfully managed 3 managers with 57 direct developer direct reports for a Software vendor in the Property & Casualty Insurance industry. (Insurnet)

EDUCATION/CERTIFICATIONS

BS, Organizational Leadership PMP Certification (535147 - lapsed) Citizenship Biola University, La Mirada, CA PMI, Newtown Square, PA **USA**